你为什么这么确定
So what makes you so sure
阿丽克西斯对这个男生不是认真的
that Alexis isn't serious about this guy?
我没见过他  也没认可他
Well, I haven't met him or approved of him yet
所以必须不是认真的
so it can't be serious.
所有追求者必须
All suitors must be
由我亲自见过并恐吓一番
met and intimidated by me personally
才有可能成为正式男友
before they can be considered for official boyfriend status.
是我就不会那样做
I would not do that.
她的尸体之前在那个桶里
Her body was in that barrel over there,
被焚烧过了  面目全非
Burned, and I mean beyond recognition.
有没有可能确认身份
Any chance of a positive I.D.?
指纹是不可能了
Not from fingerprints.
从骨架可以看出是名年轻女性
But bone structure tells me it's a young woman,
大约1米62
About 5'4".
外来游客吗
So a transient?
不太像  她的后脑中枪
I doubt it. There's a bullet hole in the back of her head
还有她的牙齿
and then there's her teeth.
全被拔掉了
Every one of them was knocked out of her mouth.
牙齿记录也查不到了
So much for dental records.
显然有人费尽心思
Well, someone obviously went to great lengths
确保她消失
to make sure she disappeared.
没有人看到任何情况
So... none of these guys saw anything.
他们白天行乞
They panhandle by day.
到天黑才会回来
Don't come back here till it's dark.
第一个来这里的人说
The first guy who showed up said
当时已经着火了
the fire was already going.
听起来像是弃尸
Sounds like a dump job.
好吧  被害人是女性
All right. We have a female.
身高1米62  去查查失踪人口记录
She's 5'4". Let's start looking through missing persons reports.
等等
Wait.
也许没必要这样做
You may not have to do that.
下颚处有个钛合金螺丝
A titanium screw from her jaw.
牙移植
Dental implant.
这上面有批号
And there's a batch number,
有可能会查出名字
which could give us her name.
根据牙科记录查到死者是梅兰妮·罗杰斯  27岁
We traced that dental screw to Melanie Rogers, 27.
住在新泽西罗格斯大学附近
Lived in New Jersey near Rutgers University,
她是博士后工程师  专攻环保化设计
where she was a postdoc engineer in eco-friendly design.
大家都说  她受人欢迎  尊敬
By all accounts, she was well-liked, respected.
我调查的人中  都想不出谁会对她下毒手
No one I spoke to had any idea who could've done this to her.
新泽西的工程师怎么会
What's an engineer from New Jersey
被弃尸在曼哈顿贫民区的桶里
doing in a barrel in lower Manhattan?
不知道  但她肯定碰到了什么麻烦
I don't know, but something was going on with her.
我调出了她昨天的电话记录
I pulled her phone records for yesterday.
她在20分钟内  给同一个号码
She made a half a dozen calls to the same number
打了六通电话
in a 20-minute period.
-男朋友吗  -有可能
- Boyfriend? - Could be.
区号是202  但是具体信息被屏蔽了
It's a 2-0-2 number, but it's listed as blocked.
202  那是华盛顿特区
2-0-2. Uh, that's Washington, D.C.
对  初步调查对方是手机
Yeah. Preliminary check shows it's a cell phone.
这意味着电话的主人有可能就在这里
Which means whoever it is might be in the city.
去申请调查这个号码的许可令
Let's get a warrant on that phone number.
大约下午四点  她又打了一通电话
She made one other call after that, around 4:00 P.M.
那之后  电话就没有记录了
And then after that, all her phone activity went dark.
她打给谁的
Who was the call to?
她同父异母的姐妹朱莉
It was to her half sister Julie.
我查了下  这是她的唯一亲人
I took a look. She's her only family.
她是市中心的信贷员
She works as a loan officer in midtown.
带她来问话  可能会有线索
Bring her in. She might be able to shed some light.
梅兰妮和我并不亲近
Melanie and I were never all that close.
但我们的父亲生病后
But when our dad got sick, we, um...
我们才真正了解彼此
We found each other.
你知不知道
Do you have any idea
你姐姐昨天来市里做什么
what your sister was doing in the city yesterday?
不知道  她偶尔会来
No. She came in from time to time.
你知道她最近有和谁约会吗
Do you know if she was dating anyone recently?
或许是华盛顿的人
Someone from D.C. perhaps?
我不太清楚
Not that I knew about.
不过
Although...
两天前  我们一起吃晚餐
Just two nights ago, she met me for dinner.
她提到稍后会去见一个朋友
She mentioned meeting a friend afterwards.
她有说是谁吗
Did she say who?
我问了
Well, I asked,
但她说出于某些原因不能说
but she said she couldn't talk about it for some reason.
那你昨天和她通电话时
So when you spoke with her yesterday,
有没有觉得有些不对劲
did it sound like anything was wrong?
我昨天没和她通电话
I never spoke to her yesterday.
她的电话记录显示昨天四点打给你了
Her phone records indicate she called you about 4:00.
四点吗
4:00?
不  我当时在开会
N-no. I was in a meeting.
我的天
Oh, my god.
她留了条口信
She left a message.
是我  听着  我觉得出事了
It's me. Listen, I think something's going on.
有些事不太对劲
Something's not right.
我敢肯定有人要对我不利
I'm pretty sure someone's after me.
她在停车场
She's in a parking structure.
有两组脚步声
You can hear two sets of footsteps.
如果我有不测  跟他们说XT3
If anything happens, tell them X-T-3--
就这样了
That's it.
她录下了自己的凶杀案
She recorded her own murder.
停车场  字母和数字
Okay, parking structure, letters and numbers.
听起来像是在念车牌
Sounds like she's reading off a license plate.
跟踪她的人的车牌
Of the guy that was following her.
包含XT3的车牌有千千万
And X-T-3, I mean, there's gonna be thousands of plates with that partial.
能再放一遍最后一段吗
Can you play the end again?
手机掉地之后好像还有声音
I thought I heard something after the phone hit the ground.
如果我有不测  跟他们说XT3
If anything happens, tell them X-T-3--
就这里  听到了吗
There. Did you hear that?
是咔嗒声
There's a click.
我处理一下
Let me see what I can do with that.
是打火机
It's a lighter.
芝宝打火机
That's a Zippo lighter.
他杀了梅兰妮
So he killed Melanie
然后停下点了根烟
and then stopped to have a cigarette.
也就是说嫌犯也许是个精神病
Which means we might be dealing with a psychopath.
那个华盛顿号码
So that D.C. number?
看来机主在城里
Looks like whoever owns it was in town.
那天她跟妹妹吃完晚餐
She called it the other night
马上就打了这个号码
right after dinner with her sister.
就是她说要去见个人那会儿
When she said she was meeting someone.
没错
Yeah, that's right.
信用卡记录显示
Credit card record says that
她几分钟后就上了的士
she was in a cab just a few minutes later.
我查到了的士司机  他说晚上十一点
I tracked down the driver. Said he dropped her off
送她去了斯坦宾馆
at the Standish Hotel at 11:00 p.m.
也许她去幽会那位华盛顿朋友了
Perhaps she was meeting her Washington friend for a secret tryst?
说得通
It makes sense.
谨慎的已婚男士都喜欢去斯坦
The Standish is popular with married men who value discretion.
也许酒店里有人看到他们在一起了
Maybe someone at the hotel saw her with him.
我真不确定
I'm really not sure.
每天那么多人来来往往
Uh, so many people come through here everyday.
再看清楚点
Look again.
记住  这是凶杀案调查
And keep in mind, this is a murder investigation.
我也许见过她几次
I might have seen her a few times.
两天前那个晚上呢
What about two nights ago?
可能见过吧
Yes. Probably.
有人跟她一起吗
Was she meeting someone?
告诉我是谁
I'm gonna need a name.
我们的客户很重视隐私
Look, our clients value their privacy.
你这样让我处境很尴尬
You're really putting me in an awkward position here.
你觉得这样就尴尬了
Oh, you think this is awkward?
等我拿授权令来
Wait till I get a warrant
审问过去一年里所有
and start questioning all the people that have stayed here
住过这里的人
over the past year.
好吧
Fine.
不是我告诉你们的
You didn't hear it from me.
不会吧
It can't be.
梅兰妮在跟布莱肯参议员偷情
Melanie was having an affair with Senator Bracken.
没错了  埃斯波西托证实了
That's it. Esposito's confirmed it.
梅兰妮打的那个号码
The number that Melanie was calling
是布莱肯参议员的手机号
was Senator Bracken's cell phone.
半夜三更的电话  酒店秘密私会
Late-night phone calls, secret hotel meetings--
布莱肯在跟梅兰妮偷情
Bracken was having an affair with Melanie.
她肯定成了他的累赘
She must have become a liability.
要不然就是无意中发现他的丑事
Or she stumbled on to something that he was involved in
对他构成威胁
and became a threat.
于是他就用对付你母亲
So he dealt with her
和打算对付你的方式
the same way he dealt with your mother
解决了她
and tried to deal with you.
时机到了  卡塞尔
This is it, Castle.
我终于有机会让他付出代价了
This is my chance to finally make him pay.
是的  但我们得小心处理
Yeah, but we have to be cautious.
我们都知道追查他的人有什么下场
We know what happens to people who go after him.
但这次  他还不知道我们查到他身上了
Except this time, he doesn't know we're on to him.
我们可以先发制人
We've got the advantage here.
是吗
Do we?
如果他知道你要对付他  他会做出什么来
What do you think he's gonna do when he sees you coming?
你觉得他害死了多少人才爬到
How many people you think this bastard put in the ground
现在的位置
to get here?
记住  我们只是来
Hey, remember, we're only here
问他梅兰妮去过哪些地方的
to see if he can help us locate Melanie.
我知道
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
让他觉得这次也能如平时一样
Let him think he got away with it,
逃脱法律的制裁
just like he does everything else.
我真希望下次与他碰面时
You know, I was really hoping the next time I saw this guy
是我用枪指着他
it would be down the barrel of my gun.
你真的不肯改变心意吗
You're sure I can't change your mind?
我这次真需要你帮忙  比尔
I could really use your help on this one, Bill.
能帮上的我一定帮  你知道的
I would if I could. You know that.
你也知道本次立法对我来说有多重要
You also know how important this legislation is to me.
参议员
Senator.
有两位警探来找你
Some detectives are here to see you.
抱歉打扰  参议员
Sorry to trouble you, senator.
不需要很久的
This won't take long.
怎么了  比尔
What's this about, Bill?
我也不清楚
I'm not sure.
你看着很眼熟
You look familiar.
我们见过吗
Have we met?
应该没有  先生
I don't think so, sir.
有地方让我们私下谈谈吗
Is there someplace we can talk?
我很想给你俩倒杯酒
I'd offer you both a drink,
不过我感觉你们是为公务而来
but I get the feeling this is an official call.
我们只是想就某个人问你几个问题
Well, we'd just like to ask you a few questions about someone.
梅兰妮·罗杰斯
Melanie Rogers.
当然  我认识梅兰妮
Yeah, sure. I know Melanie.
她是个好女孩  出什么事了吗
She's a great girl. Is there a problem?
她  她失踪了
She's--she's missing.
昨天不见的
Since yesterday.
失踪了
She's missing?
太不幸了  我能做些什么
That's terrible. Whatever I can do to help.
你最后一次见到罗杰斯女士是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Ms. Rogers?
就在昨天  我们都参加了
Just yesterday. We were both attending
市里的一场环境研讨会
the same eco conference in the city.
你在那里遇到她的吗
Oh, so you ran into her there?
不是  我要上台演讲
No. I'm, uh, giving the keynote address,
她是来帮助我准备演讲
and she was helping me with my speech.
这么说她是为你工作
Oh, so she works for you.
也不算  她同意给我做顾问
Not exactly. She agreed to consult with me
磋商一项我正准备提出的
on a very important piece of legislation
重要立法
that I'm unveiling.
这么说她是个免费顾问
So she's a non-paid consultant?
是的
I suppose.
怎么了
Why?
有人指证两天前
It's just that you were seen
你们曾一起出现在斯坦宾馆
at the Standish hotel together two nights ago.
你在暗示什么
What are you implying?
我们只想建立一条时间线
We're just trying to establish a timeline
找出梅兰妮的下落
of melanie's whereabouts.
才不是
The hell you are.
你们在利用职务之便
You're trying to take a professional relationship
想要诬陷我
and use it against me.
听着  伙计  我们不是想陷害...
Look, man. We're not trying to jam you up--
我知道在哪见过你了
I know where I've seen you.
你是贝克特探长的同事
You work with Detective Beckett.
我们还有几个问题
We just have a few more questions.
找我的律师去
Then call my lawyer.
这家伙肯定有罪
The guy's guilty as hell,
但他有不在场证明
but he has an alibi.
他整天都在参加会议
He was at some conference all day.
莱恩正在核查
Ryan's checking it out now.
会被确实的
It's gonna check out.
他从不自己出手
He never does this on his own.
都是派别人去
He always sends someone else.
好吧  那么...
Okay, okay, so...
我们不仅得找出凶手
Now not only do we have to find this killer,
还得找到他跟布莱肯的关系
but we have to connect him to Bracken.
只是我们毫无头绪从何下手
Except we have no idea where to start looking.
我们连犯罪现场都没找到
We don't even have a real crime scene.
的确  但我们有进展了
No, but we're getting closer.
联调局分析了梅兰妮的语言留言
The FBI performed an analysis of Melanie's voice mail.
这通电话来自一个停车场
It was a call made from a parking garage
她在那里被绑架的
where she was abducted.
他们分析出背景噪音是来自
They identified the background noise
TC5015塔式起重机的液压发动机
as the hydraulic motor of a TC5015 tower crane.
塔式起重机常用于大型工程
Tower cranes are used in heavy construction.
也就是说车库靠近一个建筑工地
Which means the garage is near a construction site.
市里只有12所工地
And only 12 sites in the city...
在用这个型号的起重机
are currently using that crane.
布莱肯的不在场证明核实了
Hey. So Bracken's alibi checked out.
目击者称他昨天全天下午都有列席
Witnesses put him at the Goldman ecological conference
古德曼环境会议
all afternoon yesterday.
他们同时确认梅兰妮也在
They also confirmed that Melanie was there,
正如他所说
just like he said.
她于3点45离开
She was seen leaving at 3:45.
梅兰妮在停车场留言的时间是4点钟
Melanie left the voice mail from the parking garage at 4:00.
会议的举办地在哪里
Where was that conference being held?
市中心的韦德马克宾馆
At the Widmark hotel downtown.
韦德马克  五个街区至外地刚好有个建筑工地
The Widmark--that's five blocks from that construction site.
旁边刚好有个停车场
Which is right next to a parking garage.
贝克特
Hey, Beckett.
你得过来看看
You need to see this.
XT3
X-T-3.
正如梅兰妮留言所说
Just like in Melanie's voice mail.
查了车牌吗
Did you run the plates?
查了  是被偷车牌  四天前报的案
Yeah. Just came back stolen. Reported four days ago.
好  你们检查下车内
All right. You guys check inside.
埃斯波  把后车厢打开
Espo, pop that trunk.
我可能说的不准
I may be wrong,
但这看起来像把狙击步枪
but that looks like a sniper rifle.
你不会错的
You wouldn't be wrong.
看  韦德马克宾馆  就是会议所在地
Yo. Widmark hotel. That's where that conference is.
布莱肯不是说他过几天要在那演讲吗
Didn't Bracken say he was giving a speech there in a couple of days?
我觉得布莱肯不是凶手
I don't think Bracken's our killer.
他不是
He isn't.
他是击杀目标
He's the target.
根据我们在车里发现的证物
Based on what we found in the car,
有人计划在明晚的环境会议上
someone was planning on shooting the senator
趁议员做主题演讲之时
at the eco conference tomorrow night
将其射杀
while he delivers his keynote speech.
如果疑犯仍未落网
And if our suspect is still out there,
他仍旧构成威胁
he's still a threat.
行李袋上有提取到指纹吗
Did we get any prints off that duffel bag?
尚未  长官
Uh, not yet, sir.
鉴证组还在检查汽车  笔记本
C.S.U. is still dusting the car, the notebook,
和包内的其他物品
and everything else in the bag,
包括狙击步枪
including the rifle.
但是狙击步枪上有序列号
Now we have serial numbers on the rifle,
我们正在调查
and we're looking into those.
被害人呢
And our victim?
梅兰妮·罗杰斯是怎么卷进来的
How did Melanie Rogers get mixed up in this?
她不知怎么撞破了他的计划  被他杀害了
Somehow she stumbled upon his plot, and he killed her.
不好意思
Oh, excuse me.
市长找我
It's the mayor.
有情况向我报告
Keep me posted. Mm-hmm.
我们或许有潜在凶犯的相貌描述了
We might have a description of our potential shooter.
韦德马克的保安拦下过
Widmark security stopped someone from
一个企图无证进入会议现场的人
getting into the conference without proper credentials.
什么时候
When?
两天前  白人  戴棒球帽
Two days ago. A caucasian, baseball cap,
留胡子  长发打卷
beard, long stringy hair,
而且还带着一个灰色大帆布袋
and he was carrying a large gray duffel bag,
-就像这个一样  -什么时间
- just like that one. - What time?
他们说是在下午3点45分左右
They said it was about 3:45 P.M.
那正好是梅兰妮离开会议现场的时间
That's when Melanie left the conference.
在语音留言中  她提到感觉事有蹊跷
In her message, she said something wasn't right.
是不是她看到那个男人  跟踪他去车库了
What if she saw this guy and followed him to the garage?
叫上埃斯波和人像画师
All right. Grab Espo and a sketch artist.
去韦德马克酒店跟保安谈谈
Go down, talk to security at the Widmark.
一小时内  我要那个男人的大概肖像
I want a picture of this guy in circulation within the hour.
明白
Yeah.
凯特
Kate.
我本以为到了将他扳倒的时刻  卡塞尔
I was finally gonna put this guy away, Castle.
可如今我却在保护谋杀我母亲的男人
And now I'm protecting the man that murdered my mother.
议员先生  我们可以提供
Senator, we can provide you
更严密的安保措施
with an increased security detail.
但在我们逮捕那个男人之前
But until we apprehend this man,
我建议您推迟演讲
I'd recommend you postpone your speech.
有必要吗
Is that really necessary?
这事不是已经在掌控之下了吗
I mean, isn't the threat all but neutralized?
但我们还没阻止他
But we haven't stopped him.
我们谈论的是一个穷凶极恶
Look, we're talking about someone that is ruthless,
且有条不紊的罪犯
methodical.
他杀害梅兰妮·罗杰斯
Someone that killed Melanie Rogers
只是为了堵住她的嘴
just to keep her from talking.
那表明了他对这事
That suggests a person that is
是不达目的绝不死心
intent on seeing this through.
没错  但你也说了
Yes, but you just said
会加强安保措施
you could increase his security detail.
这可不是一般的会议
Look, this isn't just any conference.
在这次的演讲中  参议员将会
The senator is going to unveil
提出一个影响深远的环保法案
a far-reaching environmental initiative
这将是他政治生涯中的一块基石
that is the cornerstone of his term.
况且我们已经发了媒体入场证
We have issued dozens of press credentials--
议员先生  我们无法保证您的安全
Senator, I cannot guarantee your safety.
我要做演讲
I'm speaking at that conference.
这将是把我推上
This keynote address
国家舞台的主要政治观点
puts me on the national stage.
我是不会因为
I'm not going to run and hide
一个疯子和他的笔记本恐吓我
just because some wacko with a notebook
就躲起来的
made a threat.
不管用什么方法
Now I suggest that
你们最好能阻止这个疯子
you people do whatever it takes to stop this man.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧  议员先生
Very well, Senator.
贝克特探长需要跟您谈谈
Detective Beckett will need a moment with you.
为什么
Why?
因为她是这次调查的负责人
Because she's leading the investigation.
有什么原因
Is there some reason why
让您觉得与贝克特探长合作不妥的吗
you don't want to work with Detective Beckett?
那我们私下谈吧  好吗  探长
Let's find somewhere private, shall we, Detective?
好了
Well...
真是讽刺呀
Hard to miss the irony of this situation.
布莱肯议员  您有敌人吗
Senator Bracken, do you have any enemies?
您觉得有什么人
Is there anyone that you can think of
想杀了你
that would like to kill you?
我常常收到恐吓信件和电邮
I get threatening letters and e-mails all the time.
当上参议员都这样
Comes with the office.
我的幕僚长收集了一个文档
My chief of staff keeps a file.
有做出实质性恐吓的人吗
Anyone with a legitimate claim?
要想做到我这个位置
A man doesn't get to my position
免不了要得罪一些人
without upsetting people along the way.
但他们大多数还没疯到
Most of them aren't crazy enough
想杀我的地步
to want to try to kill me,
你就另当别论了
present company excluded.
议员先生
You know, Senator...
现在我并不是你需要提防的人
I'm not the one that you should be worried about right now.
探长  这儿只有我俩
It's just us here, Detective.
一个在逃枪击犯
A shooter on the loose,
瞄准我为目标
me in the crosshairs...
这一定是你的美梦成真时刻
Must be a dream come true for you.
在我的美梦里
In my dreams,
扣动扳机的人是我
I'm the one that gets to pull the trigger.
但你知道吗
But you know what?
如果你觉得由我来负责调查不妥
If you're not comfortable with me leading this investigation,
你尽可以到外面告诉大家
you're welcome to step outside
为什么你觉得不妥
and tell everyone why.
那我猜  我们是暂时甩不掉对方了
Well, then I guess we're stuck with each other.
有一件事  我要说清楚
So then let me make one thing clear.
这个人杀害了梅兰妮·罗杰斯
This man killed Melanie Rogers,
当有人犯下谋杀罪行时
and when someone commits murder,
无论他是什么人  议员先生
whoever he is, Senator,
我都会将他绳之以法
I will bring him to justice,
不管这过程需要多久时间
no matter how long it takes.
我会让我的办公厅主任把恐吓信给你送来
I'll have my chief of staff send over the letters.
我告诉你  如果我是她
I'll tell you something, if I'm her,
我就在这坐着  捣腾书面文件
I sit in there shuffling papers till whoever it is
直到那家伙把布莱肯的脑瓜打开花
puts a bullet in Bracken's head.
不  你不会的
No, you wouldn't,
因为那会使你变成和他一样
'cause that would make you no better than he is.
他杀了贝克特的母亲
The guy murdered Beckett's mother,
蒙哥马利警监
Captain Montgomery,
谁知道还有什么人
who knows who else.
布莱肯罪有应得  就让老天惩罚他吧
Bracken's got it coming to him, so I say, let it come.
市长问有什么新情况  有吗
Mayor's asking for an update. What's the latest?
来福枪上的序列号领我们找到了
The serial number on that rifle
一家新泽西州佩特森市的打猎用品店
led us to a hunting store in Paterson, New Jersey.
店主根据画像确认了嫌犯来过
The owner IDed our susppect from the sketch.
店里的记录指出他还购买了其它一些枪支
The paperwork indicates that several firearms were purchased,
但他留下的姓名和地址都是假的
but the name and address are all bogus.
领几个人去排查商店周围的区域
Okay, take a few units to canvass the area near the store
记得带着疑犯画像
and take the sketch of our suspect.
好的
All right.
埃斯波西托警探
Detective Esposito.
-鉴证组有新消息吗  -有  长官
- Any word from CSU? - Yes, sir.
他们在行李袋里发现了
They discovered part of a receipt
一小块脏兮兮的收据
with a smudge on it in the duffel bag.
正在想办法提取部分指纹
They're trying to get a partial print off of that.
虽然收据上没写销售点
Now there's no point of sale on the receipt,
不过上面的库存检索码和这顶帽子的一样
but the SKU number matched that hat.
制造商把三州地区的经销网点
The manufacturer's sending over
发过来了
a list of outlets in the Tristate area,
但有200多个
but there's over 200 locations.
先重点排查新泽西的店
Focus on the ones in Jersey first.
离布莱肯演讲还有24小时
24 hours before Bracken speaks--
也许贝克特在恐吓信里能有什么发现
maybe Beckett will have better luck with those threat letters.
老天  这些人真该过过正常的生活
Man, these people need to get a life.
看起来这些人唯一的伙伴是
Most of these guys, it seems their only companionship
只能用微波跟他们交流的外星人
is the space alien that talks to them through their microwave.
这世上有很多孤独而困惑的人
Yeah, well, there's a lot of lonely and confused people out there.
目前为止  没有一封信的笔迹
But so far, none of the letters
和嫌疑人笔记本上的相同
match the handwriting in our suspect's notebook.
凭着布莱肯的能力
Considering what he's capable of,
你不觉得他的敌人会更"高级"一点吗
you would think Bracken would have more formidable enemies.
显然你还没看见我写给他的信
Oh, obviously, you never saw the letter that I sent him.
事实上  我看见了  我喜欢你那种写法
No, I did, actually. I liked the way you, uh,
把"杀"上面的叉画成了一颗小心心
dotted the "I" on "Kill" with a little heart.
手法很赞
It was a nice touch.
我想呈现私人恩怨的感觉
Well, I was trying to give it a personal feel.
干得好
Well done.
我们真的不需要谈谈吗
So we're really not gonna talk about this?
卡塞尔  有什么好谈的
I mean, Castle, what is there to talk about?
说实话吗  所有事都需要谈
Honestly? Practically everything.
正因如此  我能做的就是客观
Which is why all I can do is treat it like another case,
因为它就是平常案子
'cause that's what it is. It's...
和其他案子一样
just like any other case.
你累了  卡塞尔
You're tired, Castle.
不如你去休息吧
Why don't you go get some rest?
不不不  如果你想  我就陪着你
No, no, no, I can stay if you like.
不用了  回去吧
No, come on. Go.
需要什么我会打给你  好吗
I'll call you if I need anything, okay?
你真的很厉害
You really are remarkable, you know that?
我现在办的案子
I'm working on this case
在找嫌疑犯
where I need to find a suspect,
我发现了一个证据
and I came across a piece of evidence.
嫌疑人写的信
It's a letter that he wrote.
没写地址  也没署名
And there's no address, there's no name,
只有新泽西的邮戳
just a postmark from New Jersey.
我深知这就是我们的突破口
And I know in my gut that this is our big break.
无论怎样  我们都会找到他
One way or another, it's gonna lead us straight to him.
但是你现在却来找我
Yet, here you are talking to me.
如果找到这个嫌犯  那么一个坏人
If we find this suspect, then someone worse,
大坏人就会逃脱正义的制裁
much worse, is going to escape justice.
我猜没有其他人知道信的事
I take it no one else knows about the letter.
是  目前还没有
No, not yet.
作为一名警官
Well, as a police officer,
你以前一定也碰过这种难题
you must have faced similar dilemmas.
是啊
Yeah.
这次有什么特殊的地方
Why is this time different?
因为这次  感觉没有正确的选择
Because this time, it feels like there's no right choice.
也许正确的选择
Maybe the right choice
就是你能接受的那个
is the one you can live with.
你们看见贝克特了吗
Hey, you guys seen Beckett?
没有  昨晚之后就没见过了
No. Uh, not since last night.
我们还以为她和你在一起
We thought she was with you.
没有  我今早打给她好几次
No, I tried her a couple of times this morning,
她都没接
but she wasn't picking up.
好的  谢谢
All right. Thanks.
我正在联系
Yo. I'm trying to get through
那些卖棒球帽的店
this list of stores that sell the baseball caps.
一半的店还没开门
Half of 'em aren't even open yet.
你那边怎么样
What about you?
啥都没有  枪的调查没有任何进展
Nada. The canvass around the gun store turned up empty.
伙计们  嫌疑犯查的怎么样了
You guys, where are we on the suspect?
不怎么样
Nowhere.
而且布莱肯议员还有不到10小时就要演讲了
And Senator Bracken speaks in less than ten hours.
恐吓信那边有收获吗
You find anything in those letters?
没什么  没有重要发现
Uh, no. Nothing significant.
你还好吗
You doing all right?
等下再说
I need a second.
伙计们
You guys...
-我刚知道一件事  -我刚从鉴证组得到
- There's something that I-- - I just heard back from C.S.U.
行李袋中收据的检验结果
on that receipt from the duffel bag.
他们在污渍上面提取到指纹了吗
They get a print off that smudge?
没有  但是里面含有
No, but it contained traces of
汽车引擎用油和刹车片残留物
synthetic motor oil and brake pad residue.
听起来这人是个修车的
Sounds like our guy's a mechanic.
所以他可能就是在修理站附近
So then maybe he was shopping for
买了来福枪
the rifle near work.
那家店在哪里来着
Where's that store again?
帕特森城  一下高速就是
Paterson, just off the highway.
就从那里开始调查
It's a place to start.
你们先去  我马上发地址给你们
All right, I'm gonna get you guys addresses on your way.
我会把方圆五英里之内的服务站
I'll compile a list of every service station
制成一个表格
within a 5-mile radius,
我们以那为中心散开调查
And we'll expand from there.
你不是要说什么吗
Were you gonna say something?
不了  没时间说了
No. We're past it.
谁能想到帕特森城会有这么多服务站
Who knew Paterson had so many service stations, huh?
我确定在倒数第五个店的时候
I'm pretty sure we left Paterson
我们就出帕特森城了
five shops ago.
20分钟后回来
Ugh. Back in 20 minutes.
我们可不能在这干等20分钟
Well, we don't have 20 minutes to waste.
先去下一家吧  一会再绕回来
Let's move on to the next on. We'll circle back around.
等一下  等一下
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
你看柜台上
Hey, look on top of the counter.
他们在卖这种帽子
They sell those hats here.
开门  警察办案
Open up! Police business!
好了  我来了  别敲了
All right! I'm coming! Relax.
别把玻璃打破了
Don't break my glass.
我看见你们了
Yeah, I see it.
-什么事  -你好
- What? - How you doing?
我们是纽约警察  你认识这个人吗
NYPD. You know this guy?
眼熟
Maybe.
他看上去像是我的一位技师
He looks like one of my mechanics.
以前的一位技师
I mean, he used to be.
我大约三周前把他解雇了
I laid him off, like, three weeks ago.
你这有什么他填写过的东西吗
Do you have any paperwork he might have filled out?
比如工作单
Maybe a work order?
可能有一些
I might have something back here.
找到了  在这里
Yeah, that's it right there.
笔迹吻合  就是我们要找的人
Handwriting's a match. It's our guy.
罗伯特·麦克马尼斯有精神分裂症
Robert McManus has a history of schizophrenia.
进过好几次精神病院
Multiple stays at a psych ward,
最近一次发病是因他儿子去世引起的
recent episodes were triggered by his son's death.
我们的部署怎么样了
Hey, where are we on deployment?
市里所以的巡逻警察都有他的照片
Every beat cop in the city has his photo.
特警组的人正在他位于泽西的家里
S.W.A.T.'s sitting on his place in Jersey,
但是他的邻居说他已经一个月没去那了
but his neighbors say he hasn't been there in a month.
他消失了很长时间
He disappears for long stretches.
我们查了他的财产情况
We're scouring through his financials,
但是数据都是很久以前的了
but they are severely outdated.
这人几年前就把他的账号注销了
The guy closed his accounts years ago.
基本上是隐居了
Basically living off the grid.
有线索了
Got something.
我们在麦克马尼斯常去的一家餐馆附近排查
We canvassed near a diner McManus used to frequent.
一个旅店接待员认出了他
An S.R.O. desk clerk just I.D.ed him.
他在那已经待了一个月了
He's been staying there a month.
纽约警察
NYPD!
纽约警察  不许动
NYPD! Don't move!
安全
Clear!
Clear.
仔细搜查房间
Take the place apart.
找出任何能帮我们抓到他的线索
Look for anything that might lead us to him.
我们应该搜查一下大楼的其它房间
We should check the rest of the building.
我去问问经理麦克马尼斯的平时生活情况
I'll talk to the manager for details on his routine.
纽约警察  把手放在我能看见的地方
NYPD. Show me your hands.
不许动
Don't move.
别跑  否则我开枪了
Don't move or I'll shoot!
我跟莱恩聊过了
Hey. I just spoke to Ryan.
麦克马尼斯仍然在逃
McManus is still out there,
但是警员们正在附近所有的大楼里
but, uh, the boys are going door to door
挨家挨户地查
in every building nearby.
他就在我的视线内
I had him in my sights.
我看到他了
I had him.
不就没打中吗
So you missed.
这事可能发生在任何人身上
So what? It could happen to anyone.
不是
No.
我不是没打中
I didn't miss.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我在那些恐吓信里
I found a letter...
发现了一封信
in the threats file.
是麦克马尼斯写的
It was frome McManus.
你什么时候发现的
How long have you known about this?
昨天晚上
Since last night.
麦克马尼斯指责是布莱肯杀了他儿子
McManus was accusing Bracken of murdering his son.
我调查了一下  他儿子24岁
I looked into it. He was a 24-year-old kid.
是布莱肯再选的实习生
He was an intern for Bracken's reelection campaign.
他原本跟一个记者约好见面
He had a meeting scheduled with a reporter,
但第二天有人发现他上吊了
and the next day they found him hanged.
你认为是布莱肯
And you think Bracken--
我也不清楚  卡塞尔  我的天
I don't know, Castle. My god.
我差一点就把证据销毁了
I almost suppressed evidence.
我本来打算把那封信烧掉
I was gonna burn that letter.
但你没有烧
But you didn't.
我不是没打中麦克马尼斯
I didn't miss McManus.
我是看到他眼睛里的那份悲痛后
I looked him in the eye and I saw his pain.
不忍心开枪
And I couldn't take that shot.
如果我想让他逃走
What if I wanted him to get away,
想让他完成计划
wanted him to go through with this?
那我又变成了什么样的人
Then what does that make me?
有什么新情况吗
Is there anything new?
关于麦克马尼斯的还没有
Nothing yet on McManus,
但是在他的房间里搜出了导线
but a search of his room turned up wires,
引爆器  还有C4的残留
a detonator, traces of c-4.
他似乎是在制造炸弹
It looks like he was building a bomb.
炸弹
A bomb? Uh...
找到炸弹了吗
Did anyone find it?
没有  如果他造了一个炸弹
No. If he built something,
要么是他带在身上
It's either with him
要么就是已经放置好就等爆炸了
or already out there waiting to go off.
贝克特  等一下
Beckett, hang on.
他有一把步枪  卡塞尔
He had a rifle, Castle.
是步枪  不是炸弹
A rifle. Not a bomb.
要是他在今晚的大会上引爆了炸弹
If he detonates that thing tonight at the conference
无辜的人就会受伤
and innocent people get hurt--
这不是你的错
Okay, this is not your fault.
怎会不是我的错  我是警察
How is it not my fault? I'm a cop.
我没有做好我的本职工作
I had a job to do and I didn't do it.
我得弥补我的过错
I've gotta make this right.
我得找到那颗炸弹  保护布莱肯的生命安全
I've gotta find that bomb and save Bracken's life.
貌似有人帮你了
Looks like you just got some help.
我们发现他在三个街区外的楼顶上躲着
Found him hiding on a rooftop three blocks away.
找到炸弹了吗
What about the bomb?
我们已经问过他了
Asked him about it.
也问了他有关梅兰妮·罗杰斯的事
Asked him about Melanie Rogers, too.
他不肯说话
He's not much of a talker.
被捕后  他一句话都没说过
He hasn't said a word since we picked him up.
带他去审讯
Take him to interrogation.
你凭什么认为他会和你谈话
What makes you think he's gonna talk to you?
因为
'Cause...
我理解他
I know him.
你好  罗伯特
Hi, Robert.
我是凯特
I'm Kate.
为什么不把手铐取下来呢
Why don't you take those things off?
戴着很不舒服吧
They look uncomfortable.
我理解失去至爱的感受
I know what it's like to lose someone that you love,
要承受那样的痛苦
to live with that pain...
忍受那种愤怒
to feel the rage
尤其是当你面对罪魁祸首时
towards the person responsible for it...
面对布莱肯时
towards Bracken.
他夺走了我的亲人
He took someone close to me.
他杀害了我的母亲
He killed my mother
他还不肯放过我的朋友
and then he went after my friends,
甚至想杀我灭口
even tried to kill me.
她是在说布莱肯吗
Is she talking about Bracken?
她只是在套话
She's... just trying to get through to him anyway you can.
那个男人杀了我儿子
The man killed my son.
没人在乎
No one cared.
我在乎
I care.
我要他血债血还
He needs to pay.
但不是用炸弹啊  罗伯特
Not with a bomb, Robert.
我们俩和他不一样
You and me, we're not like him.
我们不会伤及无辜
We don't hurt innocent people.
C4炸弹在哪儿
Where's the C-4?
你在迷惑我
You're trying to confuse me...
哄骗我
or trick me...
让我说出不该说的话
into saying something I shouldn't.
我跟你一样想要扳倒布莱肯
I'm trying to take down Bracken, same as you.
但我们得采取正确的方式
And we gotta do it in the right way.
你和我是一伙的  罗伯特
You and me are on the same side, Robert.
你和他是一伙的
You're on his side.
他控制了每个人
He controls everybody.
你们都被他握在掌心里
You're all in his pocket.
你们中的每一个人
Every last one of ya!
不  我没有
No, I'm not.
我和你一样  罗伯特
I'm just like you, Robert.
她套不出什么话了
She's losing him.
你和我不一样
You're not like me.
你在捏造事实
You're making stuff up,
编造故事
making up stories!
如果你遭受过我经历的一切
If you went through what I went through,
你也会想他死的
you would want to see him dead!
我的每句话都千真万确
Everything that I told you was true.
罗伯特  看着我
Robert, look at me.
C4炸弹在哪儿
Where is the C-4?
如果炸弹爆炸了
If that thing goes off,
我们会手染鲜血
then there's blood on our hands,
愧疚会将我侵蚀
And I cannot live with that
你也一样
and I know that you can't either.
警探  我有话和你说
Detective, a word.
-长官  -警探
- Sir.  - Detective.
长官  我能让他开口
Sir, I can do this. I can reach him.
都结束了  警探
It's over, detective.
再给我一分钟
Just give me another minute.
我刚接到联邦政府的电话
I just got a call from the feds.
他们找到炸弹了
They found the bomb.
麦克马尼斯在邮局租了一个邮箱
Mcmanus rented a box at a post office.
C4炸弹就在里面
The C-4 was there.
他把电线接到背心上
He'd wired it into a vest.
不知从哪儿拿到了会议通行证
He also obtained credentials for the conference somehow.
谢谢你  警监
Well, thank you, captain,
谢谢你所做的一切
For everything you've done.
实际上
Well, actually,
这大多归功于贝克特警探
Detective Beckett deserves most of the credit.
调查是由她带领的
She led the team.
抱歉  议员先生先生
Excuse me, senator.
下午好  市长先生
Good afternoon, Mr. Mayor.
我听说了
I heard how you led the team.
你近距离朝疑犯开了两枪
You fired, what, two shots from close range
却都未命中
and both of them missed?
嘴上总是提正义
All this talk about justice...
我没看错你
I guess I was right about you.
看看这个
Check this out.
庆祝我们侦破一桩难案
What better way to celebrate the end of a difficult case
有什么东西能胜过
than with a bottle
一瓶...你在干嘛呢
of-- what are you doing?
卡塞尔  看看这个理应是
Castle, look at this vest
麦克马尼斯制作的背心
Mcmanus supposedly made.
这些尼龙扣条和电线
The zip ties and the wires...
做工非常专业
They're expertly done.
你见过麦克马尼斯
You saw Mcmanus.
他勉强能够自己扣好扣子
He was barely able to button his own shirt.
以他的目前状态  的确不可能
In his current state, no.
但他可能是在服药期间制作的
But he could've done this while he was still on his meds.
那么梅兰妮的尸体呢
And what about Melanie's body?
他烧毁尸体  敲掉她的牙齿
He burned it and then he knocked out her teeth
使得尸体无法辨认
to keep it unidentifiable.
接着他却把行李袋留在
And then he leaves a duffel bag
一辆被偷的车里  任由我们找到
in a stolen car for us to find?
这说不通啊
That doesn't make any sense.
他精神不正常
Well, he's mentally ill.
我是说  他不一定按套路出牌
I mean, not everything he does is going to make sense.
不  卡塞尔  事情不太对劲
No, Castle. Something is not right.
梅兰妮的语音邮件里有打火机声
That zippo lighter that we heard on Melanie's voice mail--
麦克马尼斯不抽烟
Mcmanus doesn't smoke.
我们翻遍他家都没找到打火机
We didn't find a zippo in any of his things.
凯特
Kate...
算了吧
Let it go.
你用不着去证明什么
I mean, you don't have anything to prove,
尤其不用证明给布莱肯看
not to Bracken,
也不用给我  或是你自己看
not to me, not to yourself.
卡塞尔  这不是在证明什么
Castle, this isn't about proving something.
这是证据
This is about evidence.
所有这些证据
Well, all the evidence--
信  笔记本  炸弹
The letter, the notebook, the bomb--
全都指向麦克马尼斯
everything traces back to McManus
万一是有人希望我们去找他呢
What if somebody wanted us to find him?
万一是他们陷害他呢
What if they're framing him
这样一来  大家都以为威胁解除了
So that everyone would think that the threat was over
但真正的杀手还逍遥法外
while the real assassin is still out there?
马夹里的炸弹
The c-4 in the vest--
也许真凶希望我们找到那个炸弹
what if that was the bomb that we were supposed to find
但其实还有一颗炸弹安放在别处
and there's another bomb that's still out there,
这颗才是为政策演讲准备的
planned for the keynote address?
这次演讲活动的时间和地点
That's an event whose time and place
在几周前就公布了
has been known for weeks.
如果炸弹在布莱肯演讲时爆炸了
If a bomb went off during Bracken's speech,
他们可以说
They could say...
麦克马尼斯在被捕前就设好了炸弹
McManus set it before he was apprehended.
布莱肯会在八点时登场
Bracken's supposed to go onstage at 8:00.
还有二十分钟
That's 20 minutes away.
我知道我并无任何证据
Look, I know that I don't have any proof.
我知道这听起来很疯狂
I know that this sounds crazy--
而且你也知道布莱肯的演讲有多重要
And you know how determined Bracken was to give this speech.
万一你终止了演讲
If you stop it and...
却发现自己错了
you're wrong,
你的职业生涯就完了
Your career is over.
如果我是对的呢
And if I'm right?
我是贝克特探长  警号41319
This is detective Beckett. Badge number 4-1-3-1-9.
请在韦德马克酒店实行紧急疏散
I'm calling for the evacuation of the Widmark Hotel.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
卡塞尔  你去和防爆小组沟通一下
Castle, why don't you see if you can get an update
看看有没新情况
from the bomb squad?
好的
Right.
出什么事了
What the hell is going on here?
谁把防爆小组找来了
Who called in the bomb squad?
我们得到可靠消息  说有威胁
We had a credible threat, sir.
从哪来的可靠消息
Credible according to who?
我想单独和你说
I think we should speak alone.
我们认为  有个你认识的人
We believe someone that you know
想要杀你
is trying to kill you.
什么
What?
你们不是把那人关起来了吗
You already have the man in custody.
我们认为麦克马尼斯是被陷害的
We believe McManus was set up
因为他寄给你的那封威胁信
because of the threatening letter that he sent you,
这证明真正的黑手
which means the individual involved
能够接触到你办公室的文件
has access to the files in your office.
那你有证据证明这一切吗
And you have evidence for all of this?
你没有证据
You don't have evidence?
我是不想让小疏忽酿成大错误
Look, I'm not gonna make this kind of accusation lightly.
于是你就叫来了防爆小组
Are you--so you called in a bomb scare based on--
凭什么  就凭你的直觉吗
On--on what, a hunch?
我们完成了搜查
We finished our search
搜遍了主要的目标区域
of the primary target area, detective.
没有找到爆炸物
We found no explosive device.
那舞台呢  你们搜查了演讲台吗
What about the stage? Did you check the podium?
我们以议员先生演讲的位置为圆心
We swept everything in a 50-foot radius
把半径15米内的地方都搜遍了
of where the senator would be speaking.
这真是荒唐
All right, well, this is ridiculous.
我们快把大家都叫回里面吧
Let's just get everybody back inside.
议员先生  不好意思  我们还需要
I'm sorry, senator. We still have to conduct
对整栋楼做全面搜查
a thorough search of the building.
恐怕还需要几个小时
It's gonna take a few more hours, I'm afraid.
你以为我不知道你在耍什么花样吗
You think I don't know what you're doing?
你让麦克马尼斯跑了  想让他杀了我
You let McManus get away so that he would take me down,
当你的计划落空后  你就想要
and when that didn't play out, you decided to ruin
毁掉我仕途中最重要的时刻
the most important moment of my career.
这跟……
That's not what this is a--
省省吧  你就等着接受调查吧
No, you save that for the review board.
你玩过火了
You have overplayed your hand,
你看我怎么灭了你
and I am going to bury you.
卡塞尔  我不明白
Oh, god, Castle. I don't understand.
我们怎么会弄错了
How did we get this so wrong?
我们知道是在冒险
We knew we were taking a risk.
不  他们陷害麦克马尼斯
No, there's gotta be a reason
肯定是有原因的
that they were framing McManus.
他们今晚会有所行动
They had to have been planning this for tonight, here.
只有这样才说得通
That's the only thing that makes sense.
或许他没被陷害
Or he wasn't being framed.
也许他们没能把炸弹安置在室内
Maybe they couldn't get the bomb in the building.
保安部署太严了
With the heightened security,
麦克马尼斯又逍遥法外
because McManus was on the loose,
也许他们被迫制定了新计划
maybe they had to make a different plan.
把炸弹装在了更容易的地方
Place the bomb somewhere more accessible.
凯特
Kate...
结束了
It's over.
凯特
Kate!
卡塞尔
Castle...
是那司机
The driver.
宣读他的权力
Read him his rights.
他叫诺阿·查尔斯
His name is Noah Charles.
做我司机已经五年了
He was my driver for five years.
他为什么突然想杀你
Any reason why he'd suddenly want you dead?
我猜是有人给了他一大笔钱吧
I assume because someone paid him a great deal of money.
你看起来并不惊讶
You don't seem shocked.
卡塞尔先生  世界又黑又白
There's another world out there, Mr. Castle,
只是大多数人意识不到
one that most people don't see,
黑暗的那边被金钱和权力所掌控
run by money, influence, power.
黑暗面的人们会不择手段
And the people in it will do anything they can
让自己站在万人之上
to stay on top.
但这些你是知道的
But I assume that you already know that.
我做不到
I wouldn't have done it, you know,
她的所作所为
what she did.
我会站在那里旁观
I'd have stood and watched.
他不肯开口
So he's not talking.
但在他的公寓搜出了一双
But a search of his apartment turned up a pair of gloves
带有梅兰妮·罗杰斯血迹的手套
with traces of Melanie Rogers' blood on it.
他们还发现了假胡子和棒球帽
They also found a fake beard and a baseball cap
和麦克马尼斯的一样
Just like McManus'.
以便让会议上的人看到麦克马尼斯
So McManus could be seen at the conference by security.
这都是设计好的
It's all part of the setup.
梅兰妮见过诺阿很多次
Melanie met Noah a bunch of times.
那天她可能认出了他
She probably recognized him on the day,
对他的行为起疑
wondered what he was doing,
跟踪了他
and followed him.
如果她发现了他
If she got on to him,
他别无选择  只能杀了她
he would've had no choice but to kill her.
真遗憾
What a shame.
她是个好孩子
She was a sweet kid.
有时间吗
Hey, got a sec?
有
Yeah.
我们查了下你的司机
We did a little digging into that driver of yours.
发现你不是他唯一的雇主  议员先生
Turns out you're not his only employer, senator.
我们查看了他的财务情况
We took a look into his financials.
有几笔大额存款
There's a series of large deposits
转入了他的户头
made into his checking account.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
无法追踪的电汇转账  在瑞士和中东的
Untraceable wire transfers bounced through shadow accounts
几个空壳账户间周转
in Switzerland and the Middle East.
要是你就会这么干
Just like you would've done.
谢了  伙计们
Thanks, guys.
你知道谁在幕后  对吧
You know who's behind this, don't you?
我有怀疑对象
I have my suspicions.
谁
Who?
一个靠着给有权势的人做出承诺致富的人
Someone who's gotten rich making powerful people promises
那个人我还有用
that I needed to keep.
当一名造王者
What does a kingmaker do
发现王不再听话了会怎样呢
when the king no longer follows orders?
给我一个名字
I need a name.
你做的够多了  警探
You've done enough, detective.
议员先生  那个人依然逍遥法外
Senator, that person is still out there,
而我却没法抓到他
and I have no way of getting to him.
你处境危险
You're not safe.
你的关心让我很感动
I'm touched by your concern,
不过恐怕你忘记了你对付的是谁
but I think maybe you forget who you're dealing with.
先生  我们得走了
Sir, we have to leave.
根据日程表  您已经迟了30分钟
You're already 30 minutes behind schedule.
贝克特警探  你能送我出去吗
Detective Beckett, would you, uh, walk me out?
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
人不可能总是赢  对吧
Yeah, well, you can't win 'em all, can you?
我猜这意味着我欠你个人情
I suppose this means I'm in your debt.
我们之间没有任何改变  议员先生
Nothing's changed between us, senator.
即使如此
Even so,
外面的世界很危险  警探
It's a dangerous world out there, detective.
说不准什么时候你就需要朋友了
You never know when you might need a friend.
麦克马尼斯的儿子
McManus' son...
是你干的吗
Was that you?
如果我说不是
If I said no,
你真会相信吗
would you really believe me?
他在这里  议员先生
There he is. Senator!
布莱肯议员  布莱肯议员
Senator Bracken! Senator Bracken!
议员先生  议员先生
Senator. Senator!
想要谋杀你的人是你的手下是吗
Is it true the attempt on your life was an inside job?
有人目击到你的司机被捕了  你有何评论
Witnesses say they arrested your driver. Any comment?
这与你的环境法案有关系吗
Did it have anything to do with your environmental initiative?
议员先生非常繁忙
Look, the senator is very busy--
不要紧  我要发表声明
No, th-that's okay. I'll--I'll make a statement.
正如你们所知  昨晚
As you all know, last night
有人企图谋杀我
an attempt was made on my life.
尽管我没能在生态大会上
And though I was not able to introduce my initiative
介绍我的法案
at the eco conference,
但这件事坚定了
it has only strengthened my resolve
我推进这次历史性立法的决心
to move forward with this historic piece of legislation.
并且我要特别感谢
And I would like to especially thank
纽约警局的
the brave men and women
勇士们
of the New York City police department,
是他们阻止了这场阴谋
who thwarted this plot.
案件进展令人震惊
And in a shocking development,
联邦探员逮捕了本杰明·莫斯
federal agents arrested Benjamin Moss,
美国之路选举基金会的创建人
founder of the powerful super pac American Way,
此前警方确认了他和谋杀未遂的杀手的
after connecting him to payments made
雇佣的联系
to the senator's would-be assassin.
莫斯  前任总统的
Moss, a former presidential...
我的天
My god.
是本·莫斯
It was Ben Moss.
最厉害的造王者
The biggest kingmaker of 'em all.
但布莱肯仅仅导致他被捕
But Bracken only had him arrested.
以他的口气  我还以为那个人
The way he was talking, I half expected the guy
会死于"空难"
to die in a "Plane crash"
或"车祸"什么的
or some kind of mysterious... "Car accident."
不
No.
这样更好
This is so much better.
现在布莱肯成了英雄
Now Bracken's a folk hero.
政客很少会为环境立法
The rare politician willing to stand up to special interests
而不顾生命危险
even if it costs him his life.
你说得对  这个故事更精彩
You're right. That's a better story.
这样的故事
The kind of story
能帮人当上总统
that could make a guy president.
总有一天他会有所疏忽
He'll slip up eventually,
而那个时候  我已准备就绪
and when he does, I'll be ready.